instamapper.com 2010-12-30

# InstaMapper - Free Real-Time GPS Tracking

## Privacy policy

Last updated August 13th, 2008. There are no material changes in this version of the policy; we simply wanted to clarify a few points. 

#### Overview

InstaMapper's privacy policy is very simple: all data that we collect is used solely for providing a GPS tracking service to our users. In particular: 

  * We do not sell, share or otherwise disclose your data to anyone unless 1) you specifically ask us to share your location or 2) we receive a valid subpoena or court order. 
  * We do not mine your data for patterns. 
  * We do not use your data to target ads. 
  * We do not access your location data without your permission. 

#### Information that we collect

We collect the bare minimum of information required for GPS tracking. 

  * _Username and password_ \- used to authenticate users. Passwords are irreversibly scrambled before being stored in our database. We do not store plain text passwords. 
  * _Email_ \- used for notifying our users of changes in service and for resetting forgotten passwords. 
  * _GPS location data_ \- sent by your phone when you run our tracking software. We transmit the following data: your GPS coordinates, speed, altitude, heading, current time, and a randomly generated id. We do not transmit your phone number, contact lists, or any other data stored on your phone. 
  * _HTTP requests_ \- as most web services, we maintain logs of all incoming HTTP requests. Web logs contain IP addresses, requested URLs, referral URLs, and other similar attributes provided by your browser. The data is used mainly for analyzing trends. Old web logs are periodically purged. 

#### Security

Your data is stored on secure servers located in the United States. We use 256-bit SSL encryption to protect transmission of sensitive information. We have taken further steps to prevent unauthorized access to your data, including running firewall software and keeping our servers up-to-date with security patches. That said, we cannot guarantee nondisclosure of personal information due to factors beyond our control. If you suspect that your account has been compromised, please contact us as soon as possible. 

#### Cookies

At InstaMapper, we use cookies solely for session management (remembering who you are once you log in) and for storing preferences. Cookies are small text files that are temporarily stored by your web browser. Most of our cookies expire as soon as you log out or close the browser window. We recommend that you enable cookie support in your browser as many features of our website will not work otherwise. 

#### Children

InstaMapper service is intended for adults only. We will not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. 

#### Updates to this policy

We reserve the right to update this policy from time to time. If we deem the change to be material, we will post a notice on our homepage and/or send an email to our users. 

#### Feedback

If you have a question, concern, or comment about our privacy policy, please contact us at [privacy@instamapper.com](mailto:privacy@instamapper.com).
